あっ…　ありがとうございます。 なぜ　助けを呼ばぬ!?
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
ここも　こっちも 血だらけではないか！
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
何なのだ？　この生き物は
The word "unknown" holds magic. And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
余は　こいつを
They are known...
地下へ降りてパームを捜す。 うまく発見できたら 俺達に構わず　脱出してくれ。
Baffling x Turn Of x Events
オス。 玉座の間に 王と護衛軍３匹がいた場合は
You're awake? Where am I?
計画通りに行動する。 問題は　奴らがいなかった場合。
A waiting room, next to the
arena for the Final Phase.
キルアは それに　こだわってるけど…。
Upsie-daisy...
どのくらいの確率だよ？ そんな場合って。 まぁ　めったないことだと思うよ。
Right. I was in the middle
of the Hunter Exam.
でも　そんな稀が結構　起こるんだ。
Your arm will heal quickly.
矛盾してるだろ？　それって。
The break was very clean.
綿密に 相手の行動パターンを調べて 今日しかないって日を決めるだろ。
In fact, once it heals, the bone
will be stronger than before.
何時には　必ずここにいるって時に 合わせて待ってると お互いにとって予期せぬ出来事が そんな日に限って起こる。
In any case, congratulations on passing the exam.
前の仕事じゃ　よくあったんだ めったにないことが
Satotz-san, I...
その日に限って よく起こるってパターンがね。
You can't.
前の仕事なら 次に延ばせばよかった。 確実に仕留められる 次の機会までね。 けど　今回は違う。
Just as someone who has failed
the exam can no longer pass, someone who has passed
the exam can no longer fail.
時間は変えられず 動きだしたら後には戻れない。
The rest is up to you.
一瞬の狼狽が　死に直結してる。 だから　今から考えておくんだ。
If you feel you are unqualified to be a pro, you are free to destroy or
put away your license.
ありとあらゆる場合をな。 もしも 玉座の間に奴らがいなくても
You can even sell it, since no one else will be able to use it.
宮殿内部にいるなら問題はない。 ピトーの「円」は 宮殿全体と庭園を包んでも 余りある面積をカバーしてる。
However, a person who has passed the exam will
not be allowed to take it again.
つまり　俺達が突入した瞬間に あの時の超不気味なオーラを 感じ取れたら
Professional Hunters are treated well, largely due to our predecessors' efforts.
奴らは宮殿内にいるってことだ。 あとは　その　まがまがしさの 濃いほうへ向かって行けば
Hence, there are many applicants
who harbor ill intentions.
その中心に奴がいる。 問題なのは　ピトーのオーラが 感じられない場合。
If it weren't for them, we would accept every person who applied.
もしくは　宮殿内にいても なぜか「円」を使ってない場合だね。
Most professional Hunters consider
宮殿の中にいて 王を守るための 「円」をしない場合なんてあるか？ それが　あったんだって ノヴさんが宮殿に侵入した時。
this card more valuable than their own lives, yet no more than a worthless scrap
of paper at the same time. The important thing
へぇ！ そう　それが一番　不可解。
is what you accomplish once
you become a Hunter.
コルトによると ノヴが見たのは プフって奴のオーラ。
What I accomplish...
護衛軍は　王のそばを離れないから プフがいたってことは
Gon-kun, you can decide for yourself when
you're ready to use this card.
他の２匹も王と一緒に 宮殿内にいたってことだ。
I have faith in your judgment.
結果　ノヴの侵入を 許してしまったのか？
Okay.
奴の能力に 関係することだと思うんだがな。
A lot of people helped me reach this point.
じゃあ それもコルトに聞いてみようよ。 だな。
I'll use this once I've returned the favor.
恐らく　その時　ピトーは 誰かの治療をしている [TEL]　治療？
Then allow me to congratulate you. Thank you, Satotz-san.
カイトを修復したのは ピトーだってことは
What about the other applicants?
前に言っただろ。
The exam is still going on, right?
今思うと　治療の間　奴は 「円」を使ってなかった気がする。
No, the exam is over.
修復には相当の 集中力がいるってことだろう。
Really?
つまり　修復の能力を使う場合
Yes, you slept for nearly an entire day.
その間は　「円」や人形は使えない。
Really?
[TEL] これで納得だ。
The others who passed are currently
completing a brief orientation.
あの時　誰かが…　恐らく 王か　他の護衛軍かが負傷して
You will undergo the orientation later. Who failed?
その治療のため　一時 「円」と人形を引っ込めた。
It was
いや　けどよ
Killua.
誰がケガさせられるんだよ？ あの怪物達の誰かをよ。 確かに。 仲間割れか？
Why did Killua fail?
王が護衛軍の 誰かをケガさせたとか？
First, let me fill you in on what transpired
あのピトーが　王を危険に さらしてまで「円」を解いて
That will help you understand
what occurred.
そこは断言するぜ。 ってことは　ケガしたのは…。
After you fell unconscious...
だが　一番　解せねえのは 「じゃあ　誰が王を？」ってことだ。
When he wakes up, he'll probably
refuse his license. That sounds like something Gon would do.
かといって　他の下っ端じゃ かすり傷すら与えられねえし。 [TEL]　うん　だから　俺達の結論は…。
Only one person will fail this round, right? If Gon fails, wouldn't that make the
rest of our fights meaningless?
王が自分を!?
Don't worry. Gon has passed.
[TEL]　そりゃ　一体 どんな状況だよ？ 俺達だって分かんないけど そうなるんだもん。
Nothing he says can change that.
[TEL] 確かに　突然の好機に喜んで 深くは考えなかったが
If Gon were to throw a fit and kill me, we still wouldn't be able
to revoke his license. Very well.
なかったチャンスといっていい
Why did you let him win?
あっちで 何かが狂って来ている
Let him win?
ヤベェな　だんだんと　俺も 何かが起こる気がして来たぜ
I'm sure you knew how to make Gon
surrender without killing him. Given your skills.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　これより 宮殿への移動を開始する。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　Ａ－１地区の人民諸君 直ちに　ディーゴ広場へ集合せよ。
When I torture someone, I expect that person to hate me
for the rest of their life.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]
It's more effective and less stressful.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　他の地区在住者は　移動準備を 万全にしておくように！
When someone is in pain, their eyes show a gleam of hostility toward
the one responsible for that pain.
おっ　ぞろぞろ出て来たぜ。
Even with extensive training, it is difficult to suppress
that gleam of hate and rage.
いよいよ　行進開始か。
But there was no gleam in Gon's eyes.
０時決行まで　あと１０時間。
Can you believe it? I had just broken his arm.
この周囲を ５００万の人間が埋め尽くす。 ペイジンのほうは 相変わらずか？
I guess you could say that he won me over.
うん　１人だと思ってた 手だれが数人に増えたニャ。
If you need a reason, there you go.
新手　それだけのこと。 大会のどさくさに紛れて 接近して来る可能性が高いな。
Gon-kun, you were able to
win over your opponent.
なら　一番危険なのは 選別中だニャ。
Hanzo said so himself.
ええ　選別には王も参加なさると おっしゃってますし。
After that, the second match began.
われわれにとって最も怖いのは
The second match is Kurapika versus Hisoka. Begin!
王が　われわれの目の届かない 場所へ連れ去られること。 奴らの中に　物質移動ができる 能力者がいると仮定して
After the two of them fought for a while...
そいつによって 王だけが全く別の場所へ
Wha—
選別中でも ３人のうち最低１人は
I lose.
王のそばに いなければなりませんね。 王が許さないだろ ただでさえ最近
Huh? And Kurapika won. What did Hisoka say?
俺達が近くにい過ぎると 煙たがるし。 だから　王に バレないように　さりげなく。
I don't know, but Hisoka voluntarily conceded.
付かず離れず 王の周囲に気を配りながらも
The third match pit Hanzo against Pokkle.
自らも迅速に 選別を遂行しなければ。
Pokkle found himself in much
the same position as you, but he admitted defeat immediately.
自分が楽しいと 夢中になってしまうタイプ
Sorry, but I won't go easy on you. That sealed the deal.
分かりました 私が適任なわけですね。
The fourth match was between
Hisoka and Bodoro.
奴らの気配が　完全に消えたニャ。 オーラの残りかすが 全然　感知できなくなった。 恐らく　「絶」を使い 人民の行列に紛れ込んだ。
The match was extremely one-sided, but Bodoro refused to give up. However, while Bodoro
was lying on the floor, Hisoka whispered something in his ear.
お疲れ。 すげぇ人数だぜ。
And Bodoro surrendered.
一軒に１００人くらいずつ 押し込まれてんじゃねえか？ あれなら　俺達が気配を絶てば
The fifth match featured Killua and Pokkle, but as soon as the fight began,
Killua walked away.
行進にまぎれたと 考えざるを得ない。
Confidently, he declared...
そう思って行進を中断させたりは しないかな？
Sorry, but I'm not interested in fighting you.
しないね。 それは　大会の延長や 中断につながるだろ？
He must have felt that he
could win his next match.
すなわち 王の妥協　王の敗北を意味する。
However, Leorio requested that the sixth match
そんなまねは護衛軍が許さねえさ。
be postponed while Bodoro
recovered from his injuries.
大会は意地でも予定通り　行う。 明日の午後３時。
So Killua and Gittarackur fought first.
そりゃ　びた一文　動かねえ事実。
Begin! That was when Killua made a fatal mistake.
いえ　敵を完全なフリーにするのは 危険です。 抑止力のため 国民を先導している兵とともに
It's been too long, Kil.
宮殿の穴につながってる 部屋の入り口は周辺に６つ。
Brother...
護衛軍の監視が厳しく なるであろう　前方は避けて 後方のＡ　Ｂ　Ｃ辺りに 待機しよう。
Hunter Vocabulary Illumi
その入り口から 部屋に入ったら　もう
Huh? Gittarackur is Killua's brother?
俺達は　宮殿内部の出口からしか 出られないんだよな。 何だよ　ビビってんのか？
Yes, his name is Illumi.
宮殿のそばで待機するのは リスクが　かなり高い。
Hey.
かといって あまりに早く　部屋に入ったら
Killua's brother?
０時まで　外に出られない。
He used those needles to change
the shape of his face?!
確かに せっかく有力な情報が入っても こちらが対応可能な状況になきゃ 意味がない。
I heard that you cut up Mom and Milluki. I guess.
ケータイは アリの電波に引っ掛かるから
Mom was crying.
宮殿近くでは使えないしな。
Anyone would cry if their
son did that to them.
どんなアクシデントが起きて　状況が 変化するか分からないのに
Tears of joy.
何時間も部屋で待機するのは 危険だと思うぞ。
She was so happy to see that you'd grown up.
かといって　宮殿周囲が危険なのは お前が言ったろ？ ああ。
But she was worried about you leaving home, so she asked me to check up on you.
護衛軍の警戒網は ナメねえほうがいいぜ。
What a coincidence.
俺がやろう。 んっ？
I didn't know you wanted to be a Hunter.
このマンションの あらゆる出入り口から 自由に出入りできるのは　俺だけ。
I'm trying to get a license for my next job.
異常があれば知らせよう。
I don't really want to be a Hunter.
お前達はまず　この部屋で休め。
I just felt like taking the exam.
お前は平気か？
I see...
周囲の様子を探るくらいなら 問題はない。
That's a relief. Then I have some advice for you.
宮殿のそばも ピトーの「円」の外ならば…　な。
You're not cut out to be a Hunter.
ふむ　だが　くれぐれも 気を付けろよ。
You were born to be...
ピトーは通常の まるい「円」ではなく
a killer.
カイトは　それに触れた。
Is that really what he said?
触れたのは　わざとだろうな。 どれほどの強さか 知りたくなるのは
Killua mentioned his family before, but they sound crazy...
戦う者の本能だ。
He wasn't finished yet.
本能に誘われて　見誤ったんだよ
You're a puppet of darkness, without passion.
奴らの強さをな。
You don't want anything or wish for anything.
一部なら ２ｋｍほども延ばせる「円」。
As one who lives in the shadows, you can only feel pleasure
絶対に触るなよ。 フフフ…　心配するな。
when people die.
この中で誰よりも 俺が　奴らを恐れている。
That's how Dad and I raised you.
そんな　むちゃはしない。 決してな。
What would you accomplish
by becoming a Hunter?
では　今から　宮殿へ向かう！
True, I don't desire to become a Hunter. But...
列から勝手に離れた者は 即刻　射殺する！
I do have something I want...
出発！
You don't. I do!
貴様　コムギが襲われているのを 知っていたな？
What's wrong? There's nothing you really want, is there?
はっ 「円」で警戒しておりますゆえ。
That's not it!
放置しました。 今から　コムギの周囲も警戒し 何かあれば　すぐ対処しろ！
I want to become friends with Gon...
はっ　仰せのままに。
I'm sick of killing people...
一隊　数万人の行列が
Your only concern when you meet someone
is whether you should kill them.
整然と王の元へ進んで行く
That's how you were trained.
まさに　アリ　いや　レミングス
You just don't know how to classify Gon
死の行進か
because he's too dazzling for your eyes.
もうすぐ　夕闇が 周囲を覆い隠す
You don't actually want to
become friends with him. You're wrong...
モラウ達を呼んでもいい頃か んっ？
If you stay with him, you'll end up wanting to kill him one day.
あれは…
You'll get the urge to see if
you can kill him or not.
何だ？
Because you have the soul of a killer.
奴の鱗粉が微風に乗って
As we mentioned before...
集合している人民のほうへ…
Yeah, I know!
つまり…！
Killua! I don't give a damn if he's your brother.
やはり 全員の表情が意思を失い
Don't listen to him! Just beat the crap out of
him like usual and win!
うつろで弛緩している
You want to become friends with Gon?
あの粉に 催眠作用があるに違いない！
Are you daft? You already are friends!
さぁ！　列を乱さず進め！ 列を乱すな！
I'm sure that's how Gon feels!
所定の位置に着いたら待機！
Really? Hell, yeah, idiot!
決して動くな！
Really... That's no good.
単調なキャタピラー音を ＢＧＭに 絶え間なく繰り返される命令は
He considers Kil a friend.
長時間移動で疲労しきった頭に 抵抗なく染み込む
Okay, I'll kill Gon.
暗示をかけるのに 絶好の環境だ
A killer doesn't need any friends. They'll only slow you down.
選別が始まり 鮮血が周囲を赤く染めても
Where is he?
彼らは　おとなしく静かに 立ち続けるだろう
P-Please wait!
自分の番が来るまで…
The match is still...
催眠か…　なるほど。 洗脳しとけば 逃げ出す者も　いないってわけだ。
Where is he? The waiting room over there...
だが　これは　俺達には好都合！
Thank you.
あぁ。
This won't do.
われ先に逃げようとして　人と人が 将棋倒しになることがない。
I need a Hunter license to do my job...
これは　デカいぜ。 作戦決行の０時には すでに半分以上の人民が
But if I kill them, I'll fail, and Kil will pass automatically.
集合済みだと想定した上で パニックが生じれば
Oh, darn. The same thing
will happen if I kill Gon.
それだけで数万人の犠牲者が 出ると覚悟していたからな。
I know!
最大の懸念が片付いたな。
I'll pass the exam before killing Gon.
あと６時間
Bastard...
全員そろったな。
If I wait until after passing the exam, I can kill everyone here and
still keep my license, right?
パームから連絡あった？ いや…。
Yes, according to the rules.
そう。
Did you hear that, Kil?
決行３０分前まで待ってみよう。 中の様子が分かるか否かじゃ 大違いだからな。
You have to beat me if
you want to save Gon.
特に　キルアは
You can't do it.
俺と戦った時の 精神的な弱さはない
Because you're more worried
むしろ全身に 自信がみなぎっている だが　なぜだろう？
about whether or not you can defeat me.
彼が時折　消え入りそうに はかなく見えるのは
And you already have your answer:
いや　ひとの心配をしている 余裕はない！
"I'm not strong enough to beat my brother." "Never fight an enemy you can't beat."
この中で 最も不安を抱えているのは 俺自身じゃないか！
I drilled that into you...
人類の未来が俺の手に…
Don't move!
コルトは　いい奴だ
If you move an inch, I'll assume
that the fight has begun.
メレオロンもイカルゴも いいハートを持ってる 人とかアリとか関係ねえ！
And if our bodies make contact, that will also mean the fight has begun.
ハートがねえ奴なんて いねえ！
There's only one way to stop me.
そう思いたい
You know what that is.
できれば　王とも…
But don't forget...
けど　問答無用でやらなきゃ 奴らは止められねえ
If you don't fight me, your dear Gon will die.
やらなきゃ　やられる！
Take him out, Killua!
カイト…　もうすぐだよ
We won't let him kill you or Gon!
俺が必ず　必ず元に戻すから
We'll stop him, whatever it takes! Let him have it!
お前の戦いに 誰も邪魔が入らないよう
I surrender.
新しい技　「カンムル」で
I lose...
やはり 連日の無理がたたってるな
Oh, that's good!
絶好調を１００とするなら ４０…
Then the battle's over.
いや　３５ってとこか
I lied, Kil.
まぁ 泣き事　言っても始まらん
I was lying about killing Gon.
ノヴが折れた今　俺しかいない
That was just a little test.
できれば 全力で戦いたかったが
But now I have my answer.
下手に余力がない分 諦めもつくってもんだ
You don't have the right to make friends.
できる限り　ターゲットを 王から遠ざけ足止めする それに専念だ！
Nor do you need friends. You should just listen to Dad and me,
and do your job as you always have.
どうしても 立ち向かえそうにない…
When the time comes, I'll tell you to take the Hunter Exam. You don't need a license yet.
宮殿の様子を見て来る。
After that, he was reduced
to a shell of himself.
プハ！
Leorio and Kurapika tried to help, but he wouldn't respond.
息を止めるのは やはり最高で２分くらいか
The sixth match was between
Leorio and Bodoro.
本番の緊張を思うと
Bodoro had recovered,
but when the match began...
半分の１分と 考えておくのが妥当！
Begin!
明日が…　俺の誕生日！
It was over in a second. Killua had killed Bodoro.
タイムアップだ　行くぞ！
Gon.
突入まで　あと１０分
And Gon was angry.